Guide to the Vassar College Realia Collection, circa 1648-2020 (bulk 1818-2000)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- Series II. Vassariana, 1861-2020
  - Ceramics
    - Ceramic plate, Class of 1959, 2009 (Box 82)
      Small, square, cream ceramic plate with blue edging. Inscribed "59 VC 09," most like for the 50th reunion of the Class of 1959, in 2009. Handmade.
    - Ceramic plates, Class of 1912 (3), circa 1912 (Box 18)
      White ceramic plates with gold edging and seal of the Class of 1912. From senior parlor. Made by Lenox for Bailey, Banks & Biddle.
    - Ceramic tankard, small, undated (Box 21)
      Small souvenir ceramic tankard with a pink Vassar seal and black print.
    - Ceramic tankard, small, undated (Box 21)
      Small souvenir ceramic tankard with gold trim and a gray and pink Vassar seal.
    - Ceramic tankard, small, undated (Box 21)
      Small souvenir ceramic tankard with gold trim and a maroon Vassar seal.
    - Ceramic tile, [1990s?] (Box 48)
      White ceramic tile with black illustration of Thompson Library
    - China teacup, undated (Box 70)
      White teacup with gold rims and pink and gray Vassar seal
    - Souvenir VC plate, Staffordshire Pottery, undated (Box 18)
      Plate, white ceramic with blue glaze, depicting Vassar College scenes. Staffordshire Pottery.
    - Souvenir VC plate, Staffordshire Pottery, circa 1900 (Box 18)
    - Souvenir VC plate, Staffordshire Pottery, circa 1900 (Box 18)
    - Souvenir VC plate, Staffordshire Pottery, undated (Box 31)
    - Souvenir VC plate, Staffordshire Pottery, circa 1919; [Framed] (Box 88 (Oversize))
    - Vassar Cream pitcher, [1895?] (Box 4)
      Small white ceramic cream pitcher with "Vassar," ships and lavender or wheat motifs painted on it. Accompanies sugar bowl.
    - Vassar sugar bowl, [1895?] (Box 4)
      Small white ceramic sugar bowl with "Vassar," ships, and lavender or wheat motifs painted on it. Accompanies cream pitcher. No lid.
    - Wedgewood plate, "Alumnae House, 1929" (Box 55)
      10.5 inch, blue print on white.
    - Wedgewood plate, "Blodgett Hall of Euthenics, 1929" (Box 55)
    - Wedgewood plate, "Cushing Hall. From the Circle, 1929", [2 copies] (Box 55)
    - Wedgewood plate, "Kendrick House, 1929", [2 copies] (Box 55)
    - Wedgewood plate, "Lathrop Hall - Strong House, 1929", [2 copies] (Box 55)
    - Wedgewood plate, "Main Building in 1865, 1929" (Box 55)
    - Wedgewood plate, "Maria Mitchell Observatory, 1929" (Box 55)
    - Wedgewood plate, "Students Building, 1929" (Box 55)
    - Wedgewood plate, "Taylor Hall, 1929" (Box 55)
    - Wedgewood plate, "The Chapel, 1929" (Box 55)
    - Wedgewood plate, "The Lake, 1929" (Box 55)
    - Wedgewood plate, "The Library, 1929" (Box 55)
  - Diplomas
    - Diploma, Cynthia (Weed) Ritch (VC 1870) (Map Case - Drawer 45)
    - Diploma, Elizabeth (Fish) Wright (VC 1932), [Rolled] (Box 93)
    - Diploma, Lillian Berlin (VC 1896), [Framed] (Framed Storage 1.2)
    - Diploma, Mary Jane Constant (VC 1869), [Rolled] (Box 93)
    - Diploma, Non-Vassar, 1913; [Framed] (Framed Storage 1.5)
      Helen Vera Paine (VC 1911), diploma from S.M. La Regina Madre Montessori School, Rome
    - First Vassar College Diploma - Helen D. Woodward (VC 1867) (Box 89 (Oversize))
    - Vassar College certificates, Schools of Music and Painting, 1885-1894 (Box 89 (Oversize))
    - Vassar College diplomas, B.A., 1908-1920 (Box 89 (Oversize))
    - Vassar College diplomas, B.A., 1870, undated (Box 89 (Oversize))
    - Vassar College diplomas, B.A., 1868-1889 (Box 15)
    - Vassar College diplomas, B.A., 1891-1919, 1943 (Box 15)
    - Vassar College diplomas, B.A., 1915-1924 (Box 16)
    - Vassar College diplomas, B.A., 1925-1934 (Box 16)
    - Vassar College diplomas, B.A., undated (Box 16)
    - Vassar College diplomas, B.A., 1873, 1892, 1907; [Mounted] (Box 15)
    - Vassar College diplomas, B.A. and M.A., blank, 1886-1914 (Box 16)
    - Vassar College diplomas, M.A., 1873, 1882 (Box 89 (Oversize))
  - Glass Objects
    - Champagne bottle in wooden box, 1945 (On shelf)
      Champagne bottle, wrapped in Victory Flag and stored in a wooden box. Used to christen USS Vassar Victory.
    - Milk bottle, undated (Box 65)
      Glass milk bottle imprinted with "One quart. Vassar College Farms."
    - Paperweight, 1886 (Box 33)
      Domed glass paperweight featuring an image of Matthew Vassar in his top hat.
    - Paperweight, undated (Box 33)
      Domed glass paperweight featuring an image of the Vassar College Library.
    - Paperweight, undated (Box 33)
      Rectangular glass paperweight which reads "M. Vassar & Co., Brewers, Poughkeepsie, N.Y."
    - Paperweights (2), 1893 (Box 33)
      Domed glass paperweights featuring an image of Matthew Vassar
    - Reunion glass, [1971?] (Box 70)
      Heavy-bottomed glass cup with "Vassar 1930-1971" printed in red
    - Reunion wine glass, 1979 (Box 62)
      Small stemmed wine glass with "Vassar Class of 1929, 50th Reunion, June 1979
  - Groundbreaking Soil
    - Ingram Library, soil in glass jar, 1997 May 10 (Box 3)
      VC earth in glass jar, from groundbreaking for Martha Rivers and E. Bronson Ingram Library.
    - Main Building, soil in ceramic jar, 1861 Jun 4 (Box 38)
      Yellow ceramic jar of earth from groundbreaking of Main Building, dug by Matthew Vassar.
    - Thompson Library, soil in glass jar, 1903 May 5 (Box 3)
      VC earth in glass jar, from groundbreaking of Thompson Library
    - Thompson Library Addition, soil in glass jar, 1917 Mar 29 (Box 3)
      VC earth in glass jar, from groundbreaking of Thompson Library addition.
  - Jewelry - Miscellaneous
    - Bracelet, Hannah W. Lyman (Faculty), 1848 (Box 65)
      woven hair and silver - amiability prize for a class in Montreal
    - Buckle, undated (Box 59)
      VC brass buckle with Vassar seal
    - Buttons (7), 1974 (Box 65)
      Seven gold blazer buttons with the Vassar College seal.
    - Locket, undated (Box 26)
      Gold locket with miniature depicting the father of Lina G. Slee (VC 1883) and hair knot.
    - Locket (?) - Miniature portrait, undated (Box 51)
      Painted miniature of Ida M. (Hill) Starr by Lorraine (Webster) Starr (VC 1909), in a metal and glass case similar to a locket.
    - Locket, Alida C. Avery (Faculty), undated (Box 65)
      Gold locket with picture of Miss Lyman (1st Lady Principal) and lock of Prof. Wm. Mitchell's hair -- given to Alida C. Avery
    - Locket (leather), Alida C. Avery (Faculty), undated (Box 1, Section 02)
      Leather locket given by Hannah W. Lyman to Dr. Alida C. Avery (VC physician 1865-1874). Decorated with monograms of Dr. Avery and Miss Lyman. Presented by M.M. Waldron (VC 1872). Once contained a photograph of Miss Lyman, Vassar's first Lady Principal, and a lock of hair from Prof. William Mitchell. (Locket contents location is unknown.)
    - Locket, Caecilie Kapp (Faculty), undated (Box 65)
      Locket with picture of Caecilie Kapp, VC faculty
    - Tie tack, undated (Box 22, Slot 35)
      gold tie tack with "VC" on a red enamel background
    - VC Qui Vive charm, circa 1896 (Box 54)
      Gold colored metal charm with green enamel (debating club)
    - Watch fob, 1912 (Box 54)
      Gold colored watch fob with Vassar seal on black gros grain ribbon
  - Jewelry - Pins
    - Hat Pin, undated (Box 83)
      Silver hat pin with filigree dome capped with Vassar seal.
    - Hat pin, undated (Box 83)
      Silver hat pin with flat Vassar seal at top.
    - Pin-back button, undated (Box 22, Slot 33)
      Green button Pin from a Class of 1911 reunion. Metal and plastic.
    - Pin-back button, 1961 (Box 22, Slot 34)
      Pin reading "1861 I Went to Vassar 1961"
    - Pins (2), 1883-1960 (Box 26)
      2 pins, most college-related. Gifted by Fanne Hart (VC 1998)
    - Sorority pins (3), 1895-1896, undated (Box 54)
      Probably not from VC, though two appear Henriette A. Neuhaus (VC 1903). 1 - rectangular, gold with black enamel, engraved with "PKA" (Rho Kappa Lamda) on the front and "H. Neuhaus" on the back. 2 - triangular, gold with black enamel, Engraved with "Tau Tau Sigma," what appears to be three overlaid letters ("C" "P" and "I") on the front and "H.A.N. '96" on the back. 3 - Diamond, gold with black enamel and pearls, "Sigma Lamda Nu" on front, "A.D.S. '95" engraved on back.
    - SS Vassar Victory pin, with box, 1945 May 3 (Box 65)
      A gold pin the shape of a V with a bird of prey in the center. Presented to Elizabeth Gatchell Bouton christening of the SS Vassar Victory ship. Inscribed on the back with "Presented to Miss Elizabeth Gatchell, Sponsor, SS Vassar Victory. 3rd of May 1945. By Bethlehem-Fairfield Shipyard, Inc."
    - Stickpin, circa 1896 (Box 54)
      stickpin with pink enameled banner with "Vassar"
    - VC Class Pin 1867 (2) (Box 77)
      Gold colored metal (1 pos. gold) pins in leaf shape; engraved - M. L. Dickenson June 19th 1867
    - VC Class Pin 1869 (2) (Box 77)
      Gold colored metal pin - a "69" with blue enameled banner
    - VC Class Pin 1873 (Box 77)
      [Gold] pin - ornate torch shape with "73" and banner, engraved with "F. E. Durand." In blue Tiffany and Co. bag.
    - VC Class Pin 1873 (2) (Box 77)
      [Gold] pin - ornate torch shape with "73" and banner
    - VC Class Pin 1875 (Box 77)
      [Gold] pin - ornate torch shape with "75" and banner
    - VC Class Pin 1876 (Box 77)
      [Gold] pin - ornate torch shape with "76" and banner
    - VC Class Pin 1877 (2) (Box 77)
      [Gold] pin - ornate torch shape with "77" and banner
    - VC Class Pin 1878 (Box 77)
      [Gold] pin - ornate torch shape with "78" and banner
    - VC Class Pin 1878 (2) (Box 77)
      [Gold] pin - ornate torch shape with "78" and banner - broken
    - VC Class Pin 1880 (2) (Box 77)
      Gold colored metal pin of VC with 80
    - VC Class Pin 1881 (Box 47, Slot 13)
      Gold colored metal pin of VC with 81
    - VC Class Pin 1882 (Box 77)
      [Gold] pin of VC with 82
    - VC Class Pin 1883 (Box 77)
      [Gold] pin of VC with 83
    - VC Class Pin 1886 (2) (Box 77)
      1 gold pin and 1 (silver?) pin. silver pin is broken
    - VC Class Pin 1888 (Box 77)
      Gold colored metal pin of VC with 88
    - VC Class Pin 1889 (Box 77)
      Gold colored metal pin of VC with 89
    - VC Class Pin 1893 (Box 77)
      [Gold] pin of VC with 93
    - VC Class Pin 1895 (Box 77)
      Gold colored metal pin of VC with 95
    - VC Class Pin 1896 (2) (Box 77)
      Gold colored metal pin of VC with 96
    - VC Class Pin 1898 (2) (Box 77)
      [Gold] pin of black enameled "V" with [Gold] 98
    - VC Class Pin 1899 (Box 77)
      [Gold] pin with Vassar seal
    - VC Class Pin 1900 (2) (Box 77)
      Gold colored metal pin with Vassar seal
    - VC Class Pin 1901 (Box 77)
    - VC Class Pin 1905 (Box 77)
    - VC Class Pin 1906 (Box 77)
      [Gold] pin - diamond shaped with "V" and "06"
    - VC Class Pin 1908 (Box 77)
      Gold colored metal pin with torch, "V" and "08"
    - VC Class Pin 1910 (2) (Box 77)
    - VC Class Pin 1912 (Box 77)
    - VC Class Pin 1915 (Box 77)
    - VC Class Stickpin 1893 (Box 1, Section 08)
      Stickpin for the class of 1893. Belonged to Helen Douglas Woodward (VC 1867).
    - VC Pin - 1950 or 1957, undated (Box 82)
      Metal pin with a floral design, has "VC" and either "50," "57," or both in the center.
    - VC Pins - Art Club, circa 1883 (Box 77)
      [Gold] pin in shape of artist's palette set with a pearl, turquoise bead, coral bead and a faceted dark red stone (garnet?) as paint
    - VC Pins - Art Club, circa 1891 (Box 77)
    - VC Pins - Dickens Club, circa 1879 (Box 77)
      Gold colored and enameled metal pins with "BOZ"
    - VC Pins - Dickens Club, circa 1883 (Box 77)
    - VC Pins - Dickens Club, circa 1885 (Box 77)
    - VC Pins - Dickens Club, circa 1906 (Box 77)
    - VC Pins - Exoteric Society, circa 1888 (Box 77)
      Gold colored metal pin of a half face mask
    - VC Pins - Exoteric Society, circa 1890 (Box 77)
    - VC Pins - Glee Club, circa 1913 (Box 77)
      Gold colored metal pin - laureled profile and lyre
    - VC Pins - Mandolin and Guitar Club, circa 1900 (Box 77)
      Gold colored metal pin - VC and crossed Mandolin and Guitar
    - VC Pins - Mandolin and Guitar Club, circa 1911 (Box 77)
    - VC Pins - Philathean Society (?), circa 1893 (Box 77)
      Gold colored metal pin - bull's head with wings
    - VC Pins - Qui Vive, circa 1884 (Box 77)
      original pewter colored metal pin in shape of a feather (debating club)
    - VC Pins - Qui Vive, circa 1888 (Box 77)
      Gold colored metal stick pin with "QV" (w/ tiny red stones in "V") linked by chain (debating club)
    - VC Pins - Qui Vive (Green), circa 1896 (Box 77)
      Gold colored metal pin with green enamel (debating club)
    - VC Pins - Qui Vive (Green), circa 1896 (Box 77)
    - VC Pins - Qui Vive (Green), circa 1898 (Box 77)
    - VC Pins - Qui Vive (Black), circa 1900 (Box 77)
      Gold colored metal pin with black enameled shield showing gold lamp in center (debating club)
    - VC Pins - Qui Vive (Black), circa 1900 (Box 77)
    - VC Pins - Qui Vive (Black), circa 1902 (Box 77)
    - VC Pins - Qui Vive (Black), circa 1904 (Box 77)
    - VC Pins - Qui Vive (Black), circa 1906 (Box 77)
    - VC Pins - Qui Vive (Black), circa 1906 (Box 77)
    - VC Pins - Qui Vive (Black), circa 1910 (Box 77)
    - VC Pins - Qui Vive (Black), circa 1912 (Box 77)
    - VC Pins - Shakespeare Club, circa 1888 (Box 77)
      Gold colored metal stick pin with "S" attached by chain
    - VC Pins - Shakespeare Club, circa 1893 (Box 77)
    - VC Pins - Shakespeare Club, circa 1898 (Box 77)
      [Gold] "S" shaped pin with black enameled " '70"
    - VC Pins - Shakespeare Club, circa 1903 (Box 77)
    - VC Pins - Shakespeare Club, circa 1904 or 1908 (Box 77)
      Gold colored metal pin with Light blue enameled center
    - VC Pins - Shakespeare Club, circa 1913 (Box 77)
    - VC Pins - T and M (Debate Club) Original, circa 1881 (Box 77)
      original Gold colored metal stick pin with half-moon inscribed "T & M" linked by chain (debating club)
    - VC Pins - T & M (Debate Club) Original, circa 1883 (Box 77)
      Gold colored metal stick pin with half-moon inscribed "T & M" linked by chain (debating club)
    - VC Pins - T & M (Debate Club) Original, circa 1889 (Box 77)
    - VC Pins - T & M (Debate Club), circa 1895 (Box 77)
      [Gold] diamond shaped pin with black & gold enameled center (debating club)
    - VC Pins - T & M (Debate Club), circa 1897 (Box 77)
    - VC Pins - T & M (Debate Club), circa 1903 (Box 77)
    - VC Pins - T & M (Debate Club), circa 1905 (Box 77)
    - VC Pins - T & M (Debate Club), undated (Box 77)
  - Jewelry - Rings
    - VC Class Ring 1872 (Box 47, Slot 01)
      Gold ring with black stone engraved with VC, in box
    - VC Class Ring 1904 (Box 47, Slot 03)
      Gold ring engraved with VC
    - VC Class Ring 1911, [1915] (Box 47, Slot 05)
    - VC Class Ring 1913 (Box 47, Slot 20)
    - VC Class Ring 1913 (Box 47, Slot 04)
    - VC Class Ring 1914 (Box 47, Slot 15)
      Gold ring engraved with V and 14
    - VC Class Ring 1915(?), 1911 (Box 47, Slot 06)
      Gold ring with red/orange carnelian engraved with Vassar seal
    - VC Class Ring 1918 (Box 47, Slot 14)
      Silver ring engraved with Vassar seal
    - VC Class Ring 1918 (seal only) (Box 47, Slot 12)
      Red/orange carnelian stone engraved with Vassar seal [from a class ring]
    - VC Class Ring 1920 (Box 47, Slot 11)
      Gold domed ring engraved with VCand 1920. Designed by Elverhoj Colony of Artists and Craftsmen.
    - VC Class Ring 1922 (Box 47, Slot 07)
      Gold ring with red/orange carnelian engraved with Vassar seal. Designed by Elverhoj Colony of Artists and Craftsmen.
    - VC Class Ring 1932 (Box 47, Slot 19)
      Gold and carnelian signet ring, VC Class of 1932
    - VC Class Ring 1932 (Box 46, Section 11)
      Gold ring with a carnelian stone. Belonged to Priscilla Carpenter (Manning) Sullivan (VC 1932).
    - VC Class Ring 1933 (Box 47, Slot 08)
    - VC Class Ring 1935 (Box 47, Slot 16)
      Gold signet ring, VC class of 1935
    - VC Class Ring 1949 (Box 47, Slot 02)
      Gold VC signet ring, engraved with "A. E. [B?]. 49" on the inside of the band. Most likely belonged to VC class of 1949 graduate Alice "Lee" E. (Broadbent) Wolff.
    - VC Philalatheis ring, 1866 (Box 47, Slot 18)
      Gold ring with [onyx] stone with blue/greyish top engraved with VC
    - VC Philalatheis ring, circa 1869 (Box 47, Slot 10)
      Gold ring with red/orange carnelian with pinkish top engraved with VC
    - VC Philalatheis ring, 1867 (Box 47, Slot 09)
    - VC Ring, circa 1926 (Box 47, Slot 17)
      Gold ring with carnelian stone engraved with Vassar College 1861
    - VC Ring and Stickpin, circa 1932 (Box 67)
      Gold ring with VC seal in red carnelian stone; pin in shape of Vassar pennant, in red jewelry box, belonging to Elizabeth (Fish) Wright, VC 1932.
  - Medals
    - Medal, undated (Box 51)
      Medal in red wooden box, possibly related to academic achievement. Belonged to Kate Glendenning Wanvig (VC 1901).
    - Medal - FIDAC, 1931 (Box 26)
      Federation Interalliee Des Anciens Combattants (FIDAC) medal - awarded to Vassar College, Prague 1931
    - Medallion, 1904 (Box 44)
      VC Class of 1904 tree plaque, metal, reading "Servabo Fidem." Includes key
    - Medallion, circa 1905 (Box 68)
      VC Class of 1905 Tree Medallion
    - Medallion, circa 1906 (Box 68)
      VC Class of 1906 Tree Medallion
    - Medallion, circa 1907 (Box 68)
      VC Class of 1907 Tree Medallion
    - Medallion, undated (Box 51)
      Large medallion by Spicer Simpson, of Louise Hammond, VC 1909. Includes letter.
    - Medals (3), 1883-1960 (Box 26)
      3 medals, most college-related. Gifted by Fanne Hart (VC 1998)
    - Plaster medallion, circa 1942 (Box 80 (Oversize))
      Large plaster medallion with VC seal belonging to Mary Orton Westheimer (VC 1942)
    - VC medal in wooden frame, undated (Box 88 (Oversize))
  - Miscellaneous Objects
    - Bicycle license plate, circa 1964 (Box 74)
      Metal, painted red. Reads "Vassar College 25." Belonged to Gail R. Becker, VC 1964.
    - Copper printing plate, 1868 (Box 67)
      Copper Plate, Invitation to Founder's Day 1868
    - Copper printing plate, 1867 (Box 67)
      Copper Plate, Invitation to Founder's Day, 1867
    - Handbell, circa 1860s (Box 37)
      Brass bell with wooden handle. "Corridor bell or dinner bell in the '60s before electric bells."
    - Key to Class of 1915 Seal (Box 6)
      Small key that opens seal/box beneath the Class of 1915 tree.
    - License plate, between 1942 and 1946 (Box 6)
      VC bicycle license plate (numbered VC 269) issued to Mary Ellen West, Class of 1946.
    - Manufacturers Fabric Sample Book, circa 1875 (Box 52)
      Belonged to Edith Murray Wheeler (VC 1890). Paper-covered book of fabric samples.
    - Piece of marble from Main Building addition, circa 1960 (Box 66)
      Fragment of red and white marble from the lobby of "The Soap Palace," the addition to the front of Main Building built by Frederick F. Thompson and torn down in 1960.
    - Place card for supper in James Monroe Taylor's new president's house, 1896 (Box 99)
      Place card with name "Miss [Brae Kennings?]" written on wood and cyanotype of the house pasted on.
    - Plaster mold, undated (Box 63)
      Plaster mold of relief sculpture of Elizabeth Dodge (VC 1913) in side profile.
    - Slateboard, circa 1892 (Box 51)
      Small (circa 6x9 inch) slate board with writing stick and sponge eraser. Probably belonged to Elma G. Martin, Spec. 1892-1893.
    - Slide rule, Edith Roberts (Faculty), circa 1936 (Box 83)
      Slide rule owned by Edith Roberts. In leather case with half of original box. Model N4041. Serial number 524908. Date derived from serial number.
    - VC card case, leather ([MISSING since 2023])
      Leather card case from the VC Class of 1925
  - Photographs
    - Miniature photo album, undated (Box 66)
      Miniature photo album in leather case, initialed "F. H. H."
    - Photograph of portrait of Lucy Maynard Salmon in decorative case, 1938 (Box 82)
      Black and white photograph of a portrait of Lucy Maynard Salmon as a young woman, painted by Alice zur Carr Boscowitz. Mounted in a decorative metal case. Original painting is in the Loeb.
    - Shredded posture photos, Physical Education Department, circa 1950s (Box 59)
      Envelope of "shredded" (almost powdered) posture photographs shredded by the Smithsonian under the supervision of VC historian Betty Daniels.
    - Tintype of Alice (Morrison) Cathcart, Spec. 1865-1866, undated; [Framed] (Box 82)
  - Plaques
    - Ceramic plaques from the Observatory (5), undated (Box 65)
      Five white, ceramic, shield-shaped plaques labeled "OBS" (Observatory), and numbered 1, 3, 6, 11, and 13.
    - Plaque - Borden Freshman Prize, circa 1962 (Box 84)
      Brass plaque honoring recipients of Borden Freshman Prize.
    - Plaque - Easley Psychology Library, undated (Box 52)
      Brass with wood mount and screws.
    - Plaque - Herbert E. Mills, circa 1931 (Framed Storage 1.7)
      Memorial plaque of Herbert E. Mills, metal
    - Plaque - Edward Handelman Lounges (?), undated (Box 94)
      Plaque reads: "These lounges were furnished in 1973 by a gift of the James A. Macdonald Foundation in honor of the memory of Edward Handelman for his interest, and that of his family, in Vassar College."
    - Plaque - Franklin D. Roosevelt, undated (Box 14)
      Relief plaque of FDR portrait (VC trustee)
    - Plaque - Mary Bliss Dodge (VC 1913), undated (Box 94)
      Plaque reads: "This room is a gift from the Cleveland H. Dodge Foundation in Honor of Mary Bliss Dodge, Class of 1913"
    - Plaque - Three Sisters Carillon, 1955 (Box 94)
      Plaque reads: "Three Sisters Carillon - Given in honor of Eleanor Lanctot Van Horn Ex Class of 1930, Sarah Lanctot Rigg, Class of 1936, Katherine Potter Lanctot Class of 1939, Great-Great-Grandnieces of Matthew Vassar A.D. 1955"
    - Plaque - YWCA Salute to Women and Girls - Vassar College, [1989?] (Box 52)
      Wooden plaque gifted to Vassar College by the YWCA as part of their Salute to Women and Industry program, with brass-colored inlays. Includes spaces for 12 individual name inlays, but only one is filled, for "Natalie Junemann Marshall, 1989."
    - Plaque - Zuccaro Section, undated (Box 94)
      Plaque reads: "The books in this section are the donation of Carlo Zuccaro. Taormina Sicily in memory of his wife Bertha Bates of Saint Louis, Missouri, Class of 1899."
    - VC Avery Hall Plaque - Alida C. Avery, undated (Box 58)
      Brass plaque honoring Alida C. Avery, mounted in Avery Hall prior to its renovation into the Vogelstein Center.
    - VC Avery Hall Plaque - Gertrude Buck, undated (Box 58)
      Brass plaque honoring Gertrude Buck, mounted in Avery Hall prior to its renovation into the Vogelstein Center.
    - VC Avery Hall Plaque - Mabel Lockwood, undated (Box 58)
      Brass plaque honoring Mabel Lockwood, mounted in Avery Hall prior to its renovation into the Vogelstein Center.
    - VC Plaque - Class of 1890, undated (Box 74)
      Wooden shield plaque for the class of 1890, with metal lettering: "VC 1890"
    - VC seal, undated (Box 58)
      VC metal seal (bronze?) mounted on wooden shield plaque.
    - VC seal, undated (Box 58)
  - Plastic Objects
    - Fran Fest water bottle, 2006 Apr (Box 65)
      Plastic water bottle from Fran Fest, 26 April 2006
    - Plastic cup, undated (Box 62)
      pink plastic cup for VC Vice
    - Souvenir ruler and magnifying glass, 1988 (Box 66)
      Brown plastic sleeve printed with "1928 VC 1988" (Class of 1928 60th reunion?) containing a small magnifying plastic strip with ruler marks.
    - VC class of 1980 kazoo (3) (Box 25)
      red kazoos with "VC 80" in white ink